Drew Goff ux/ui designer

Phone 317-910-5607

Email

drew@drewgoff.com

Portfolio

https://drewgoff.com

Address

1184 Bridgeport Drive Westfield, IN 46074

EDUCATION

Indiana University

B.S.

General Studies

Minors

Psychology & Media Production

Recording Workshop

Cert

Sound Engineering

EXPERTISE

Technical Skills

Adobe Creative Suite, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Ilustrator, Photoshop

Microsoft Office, Teams, Visual Studio Code

Apple Logic Pro X, Presonus StudioOne

Artist and Event Photography

HTML, CSS, SVG, JavaScript & React

3D animation with Cinema 4D

Prototyping with Sketch, Zeplin, InVision and Axure

ABOUT

Worked as a UX/UI Designer for the last eight years. This includes designing websites, mobile apps, design systems and web applications. When design is not needed, I have joined software teams and performed front end development work. This includes coding in HTML, CSS, React, JavaScript and Web Components.

Where my career continues to move towards is diving deeper into product design and front end development.

EXPERIENCE

Caterpillar Inc.

(Sep 2019 - May 2020)

UX Designer & UI Developer (Contractor)

- + Brought on to design and build the 4th generation OS user interface for the Earth moving division. We designed the interfaces and coded them as web components (JavaScript, Shadow DOM, HTML, CSS, SVG) to support nine software teams around the world.
- + Created Axure Pattern libraries for our design system.
- + Wrote scripts, designed storyboards, did voiceover and created 2D/3D animations; in teaching the high level management about the cost benefits of creating a Design System for Caterpillar vehicles.

UX Coding

(Mar 2019 - Present)

Product Designer

- + Creating a Instructional design video series that teaches front end development to UX Designers so that they can become UX Developers.
- + What separates this course from others is that I have been a UX Designer, so I understand the cognitive psychology of UX Designers. Most people who teach programming courses are programmers who do not understand the way that designers learn.
- **+** My role as the product designer has been:
 - User research (market research, personas, customer journey mapping)
 - Product design (wireframing, interface design, A to B testing)
 - Media creation (Script writing, Storyboarding, 3D animations)
 - Programming (Coded website & app in JavaScript, Node.js and SQL)
 - Marketing (Cold emailing, SEO, Linkedin marketing)

Drew Goff ux/ui designer

Phone 317-910-5607 **Email** drew@drewgoff.com

Portfolio
https://drewgoff.com

1184 Bridgeport Drive Westfield, IN 46074

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Deaconess Children's Hospital

Worked on a team of designers, creating the designs for the new children's hospital. My primary role was as the photographer on the team. The large scale photography work is showcased throughout the hospital.

REFERENCES

Tom Beccuee Manager at Caterpillar 309-202-7455

Sarah Schonert Team Lead at Caterpillar 309-645-3619

Ryan Stephens Technology Manager at Kroger Technology 270-832-5443

Tara Blessinger Deaconess Designer 812-431-6199

Laura Brown Marketing Manager 812-604-5649

EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED

SIGMA Equipment

(Sep 2016 - Feb 2019)

Address

UX/UI Designer

- + Work on a team of six developers as the sole UX Designer/Developer.
- + Designed software interfaces using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.
- + Coded the interfaces in HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, JavaScript, React, JSX, Babel, NPM and Visual Studio Code.
- + Meet with business analysts and project managers to design projects to business requirement standards.

OneMain Financial

(Dec 2014 - Sep 2016)

UX/UI Designer

- + Developer and designer of the framework "OneMain Elements". What makes Elements unique is it's build using Object Oriented SASS (CSS) and vanilla Javascript. What really makes it different though is that every object has been designed for exact measurements in Adobe Illustrator. This allows us to expedite UI development by reusing code and to create consistency among designs.
- + UX Designer/Developer for OneMain Financial & Springleaf Financial's phone and tablet applications.
- + UX Designer/Developer for OneMain Financial & Springleaf Financial's infonet and internal web applications.

CNO Financial Group

(Dec 2014 - Sep 2016)

Web Designer

Truth@Work

(Jun 2012 - Jun 2014)

Director of Web and Multimedia Development

INDYCAR Driver Simona De Silvestro

(Jun 2012 - Jun 2014)

UX Designer, UI Developer and Photographer